[
    {
        "category": "ISC2 Cybersecurity Certification",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which one of the following is not one of the canons of the (ISC)2 code of ethics?",
                "options": ["Protect society, the common good, necessary public trust and confidence, and the infrastructure.",
                            "Avoid any activity that may be perceived as malicious.",
                            "Act honorably, honestly, justly, responsibly, and legally.", 
                            "Advance and protect the profession."],
                "correct_options": [1]
            },
            {
                "question": "What security control provides non-repudiation for messages?",
                "options": ["digital certificates", 
                            "hash values",
                            "symmetric encryption", 
                            "digital signatures"],
                "correct_options": [3]
            },
            {
                "question": "Which one of the following is an example of multifactor authentication?",
                "options": ["password and security questions",
                            "retinal scan and fingerprint",
                            "ID card and PIN",
                            "ID card and key"],
                "correct_options": [2]
            },
            {
                "question": "What law regulates the protection of health information?",
                "options": ["FERPA",
                            "PCI DSS",
                            "GLBA",
                            "HIPAA"],
                "correct_options": [3]
            },
            {
                "question": "What security tool can be configured to prevent DDoS attacks?",
                "options": ["switch", "firewall", "endpoint detection and response platform", "intrusion detection system"],
                "correct_options": [3]
            },
            {
                "question": "Your organization requires that passwords contain a mixture of uppercase characters, lowercase characters, digits, and symbols. What type of password policy is this?",
                "options": ["complexity",
                            "length",
                            "history",
                            "reuse"],
                "correct_options": [0]
            },
            {
                "question": "During what phase of the access control process does a user prove his or her identity?",
                "options": ["authentication",
                            "authorization",
                            "identification",
                            "remediation"],
                "correct_options": [0]
            },
            {
                "question": "In what type of attack does the attacker capture and then reuse login information?",
                "options": ["man-in-the-middle attack",
                            "Smurf attack",
                            "DDoS attack",
                            "replay attack"],
                "correct_options": [3]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the best defense against dumpster diving attacks?",
                "options": ["anti-malware software",
                            "clean desk policy",
                            "data loss prevention tools",
                            "shredding"],
                "correct_options": [3]
            },
            {
                "question": "Purchasing an insurance policy is an example of which risk management strategy?",
                "options": ["risk acceptance",
                            "risk deterrence",
                            "risk transference",
                            "risk mitigation"],
                "correct_options": [2]
            },
            {
                "question": "What two factors are used to evaluate a risk?",
                "options": ["likelihood and impact",
                            "criticality and likelihood",
                            "impact and criticality",
                            "frequency and likelihood"],
                "correct_options": [0]
            },
            {
                "question": "What term best describes making a snapshot of a system or application at a point in time for later comparison?",
                "options": ["baselining",
                            "documenting",
                            "diagramming",
                            "versioning"],
                "correct_options": [0]
            },
            {
                "question": "What type of security control is designed to stop a security issue from occurring in the first place?",
                "options": ["recovery",
                            "administrative",
                            "preventive",
                            "detective"],
                "correct_options": [2]
            },
            {
                "question": "What term describes risks that originate inside the organization?",
                "options": ["external",
                            "intranet",
                            "internal",
                            "extranet"],
                "correct_options": [2]
            }
        ]
    }
]
